MoMA PS1 Archives
The Museum of Modern Art, Publisher
- Series I: Curatorial and Exhibition Records, (19682009)
  - Subseries I.A: General Files, (19702009)
    - "Robert Grosvenor Insurance", 1983-1984; Includes checklist of works with loan forms. Robert Grosvenor(January 22-March 18, 1984): Checklist; Loan Forms and Condition Reports; Restricted material removed: Loan forms. (Box 38, Folder I.A.830)
    - Robert Grosvenor, 1983-1984; Includes loan forms, insurance values, return receipts, correspondence, notes, sketch of installation, and other materials. Robert Grosvenor(January 22-March 18, 1984): Art and Event Photographs; Loan Forms and Condition Reports; General Exhibition Documentation; Restricted material removed: Loan forms and shipping documents. (Box 38, Folder I.A.831)
    - Robert Grosvenor, 1984; Includes loan forms, some notes, and annotated checklist. Robert Grosvenor(January 22-March 18, 1984): Checklist; Loan Forms and Condition Reports; General Exhibition Documentation; Restricted material removed: Loan forms. (Box 38, Folder I.A.832)
    - Annie Ratti, 1984; Background material only. Sofia Nicoletti & Annie Ratti(February 26-March 25, 1984): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 38, Folder I.A.833)
    - Sofia Nicoletti, 1983-1984; Includes numerous prints of works by the artist (with an original sketch), with some correspondence and background material. Sofia Nicoletti & Annie Ratti(February 26-March 25, 1984): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 38, Folder I.A.834)
    - Michael Hurson, 1983-1984; Includes checklist, budget materials, draft brochure texts by curator Henry Geldzahler, exhibition proposal, correspondence, and background material. Michael Hurson: Drawings 1969-1983(February 26-March 25, 1984): Checklist; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 38, Folder I.A.835)
    - "Michael Hurson Insurance", 1983-1984; Includes checklists, loan forms and loan correspondence, and catalog. Michael Hurson: Drawings 1969-1983(February 26-March 25, 1984): Printed Ephemera; Loan Forms and Condition Reports; Restricted material removed: Loan forms. (Box 38, Folder I.A.836)
    - Michael Hurson Returns, 1984; Return receipts, annotated checklists, notes and correspondence, and the checklist for the version of the exhibition staged at the Art Institute of Chicago. Michael Hurson: Drawings 1969-1983(February 26-March 25, 1984): Checklist; General Exhibition Documentation; Restricted material removed: Shipping documents. (Box 38, Folder I.A.837)
    - "Portrait Show Returns", 1984; Return shipping receipts with insurance values checklist. The New Portrait(April 15-June 10, 1984): General Exhibition Documentation; Restricted material removed: Shipping documents. (Box 38, Folder I.A.838)
    - "Portrait Show Correspondence", 1984; The New Portrait(April 15-June 10, 1984): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 38, Folder I.A.839)
    - "Portrait Show Insurance Lists", 1984; Includes regular checklist, as well as ones with insurance values, with some notes. The New Portrait(April 15-June 10, 1984): Checklist (Box 38, Folder I.A.840)
    - "Portrait Show Insurance Lists", 1984; Includes handwritten draft and heavily edited typescript. The New Portrait(April 15-June 10, 1984): Checklist (Box 39, Folder I.A.841)
    - "Portrait Show Signed Loan Forms", 1984; Loan forms with return receipts. The New Portrait(April 15-June 10, 1984): Loan Forms and Condition Reports; Entire folder restricted. (Box 39, Folder I.A.842)
    - "Portrait Show Checklist", 1984; The New Portrait(April 15-June 10, 1984): Checklist (Box 39, Folder I.A.843)
    - "Portrait Show" Installation Photographs, 1984; Contact sheets and negatives of installation images for the portrait show, as well as negatives for the Australian show and perhaps other exhibitions. An Australian Accent(April 15-June 10, 1984): Installation Photographs The New Portrait(April 15-June 10, 1984): Installation Photographs (Box 39, Folder I.A.844)
    - "Portrait Show", 1984; Some photographs of artworks, with catalogues of other portrait shows. The New Portrait(April 15-June 10, 1984): Art and Event Photographs (Box 39, Folder I.A.845)
    - "Portrait Show Condition Reports", 1984; Condition reports only. The New Portrait(April 15-June 10, 1984): Loan Forms and Condition Reports; Entire folder restricted. (Box 39, Folder I.A.846)
    - "An Australian Accent to Corcoran Gallery of Art", 1984; Tour contract, correspondence, notes, and other documents regarding the exhibition tour. An Australian Accent(April 15-June 10, 1984): General Exhibition Documentation; Restricted material removed: Exhibition contract. (Box 39, Folder I.A.847)
    - "Australian Exhibition Spring 1983", 1983-1984; Includes correspondence with organizer John Kaldor, budget documents, and other materials. An Australian Accent(April 15-June 10, 1984): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 39, Folder I.A.848)
    - "Chase Art Program: Purchase of Parr, Tillers, Unsworth", 1984; Small amount of materials, including condition notes on works, on the sale of works from the Australian exhibition. An Australian Accent(April 15-June 10, 1984): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 39, Folder I.A.849)
    - "Aussie Check List", 1984; Day by day condition checklists for works in the exhibition. An Australian Accent(April 15-June 10, 1984): Loan Forms and Condition Reports; General Exhibition Documentation; Entire folder restricted. (Box 39, Folder I.A.850)
    - "Aussie Show", 1984-1985; Includes map of installation, correspondence, checklists, and condition checklists. An Australian Accent(April 15-June 10, 1984): Checklist; Art and Event Photographs; Loan Forms and Condition Reports; General Exhibition Documentation; Restricted material removed: Loan forms and condition reports. (Box 39, Folder I.A.851)
    - "Australian Accent: Kaldor", 1983-1984; Includes partial checklists, notes, budget sheets, catalogue texts, and correspondence, with various notes. An Australian Accent(April 15-June 10, 1984): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 39, Folder I.A.852)
    - "An Australian Accent: Australian Biennial Catalogue", 1981; Catalogue for Australian Perspecta 1981. An Australian Accent(April 15-June 10, 1984): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 40, Folder I.A.853)
    - An Australian Accent Exhibition and Press Materials, 1984; Includes photographs and transparencies of artworks, various press releases and descriptions of the exhibition, and notes and memos. An Australian Accent(April 15-June 10, 1984): Press Release; Art and Event Photographs; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 40, Folder I.A.854)
    - "1983-1984 Dance Program; Curators: Barry Laine and Judy Padow", Includes catalogue text by Laine; information on participants, program, budgets, and correspondence for Frontline… with some additional material on the previous year's program. Spring Dance Series (1983):Dance Environments: New Collaborations Between Dancers and Visual Artists(April 23-June 4, 1983): General Exhibition Documentation Spring Dance Series (1984):Frontline: Dance and Social Commentary(April 28-June 10, 1984): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 40, Folder I.A.855)
    - "1983-1984 Dance Program: Sally Silvers", Spring Dance Series (1984):Frontline: Dance and Social Commentary(April 28-June 10, 1984): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 40, Folder I.A.856)
    - "1983-1984 Dance Program: Tim Miller", Spring Dance Series (1984):Frontline: Dance and Social Commentary(April 28-June 10, 1984): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 40, Folder I.A.857)
    - "1983-1984 Dance Program: Paula Kellinger", Spring Dance Series (1984):Frontline: Dance and Social Commentary(April 28-June 10, 1984): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 40, Folder I.A.858)
    - "1983-1984 Dance Program: Ishmael Houston-Jones", Spring Dance Series (1984):Frontline: Dance and Social Commentary(April 28-June 10, 1984): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 40, Folder I.A.859)
    - "1983-1984 Dance Program: Viveca Vazquez", Spring Dance Series (1984):Frontline: Dance and Social Commentary(April 28-June 10, 1984): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 40, Folder I.A.860)
    - "1983-1984 Dance Program: Kenneth King", Spring Dance Series (1984):Frontline: Dance and Social Commentary(April 28-June 10, 1984): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 40, Folder I.A.861)
    - "1983-1984 Dance Program: Craig Bromberg", Spring Dance Series (1984):Frontline: Dance and Social Commentary(April 28-June 10, 1984): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 40, Folder I.A.862)
    - "1983-1984 Dance Program: Stephanie Skura", Spring Dance Series (1984):Frontline: Dance and Social Commentary(April 28-June 10, 1984): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 40, Folder I.A.863)
    - "1983-1984 Dance Program: Gayle Tufts", Spring Dance Series (1984):Frontline: Dance and Social Commentary(April 28-June 10, 1984): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 40, Folder I.A.864)
    - "1983-1984 Dance Program: Sophie Maslow", Spring Dance Series (1984):Frontline: Dance and Social Commentary(April 28-June 10, 1984): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 40, Folder I.A.865)
    - Edith Segal, 1984; Includes writings by Segal, correspondence, with some other documents. Spring Dance Series (1984):Frontline: Dance and Social Commentary(April 28-June 10, 1984): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 40, Folder I.A.866)
    - "Summer Dance Residency Program 1984", Announcements and selection panel materials, with the schedule of residencies. (Box 40, Folder I.A.867)
    - "Summer Dance Residency Program 1984: Ellen Fisher" (Box 40, Folder I.A.868)
    - "Summer Dance Residency Program 1984: David Hurwith" (Box 40, Folder I.A.869)
    - "Summer Dance Residency Program 1984: D.J. McDonald" (Box 40, Folder I.A.870)
    - "Summer Dance Residency Program 1984: Bebe Miller" (Box 40, Folder I.A.871)
    - "Summer Dance Residency Program 1984: Joelle Ballonzoli (Alternate)" (Box 40, Folder I.A.872)
    - Miscellaneous Handbills, Announcements, and Information Sheets, 1984-1985; Catalogue for the 1984-1985 studio program exhibition, dance program handbills, and various press releases and seasonal materials. National and International Studio Program Exhibition 1984-1985(January 25-March 3, 1985): Printed Ephemera Film (Spring 1985) (May 5-June 23, 1985): Printed Ephemera Spring Dance Series (1985):Dance and Popular Culture(May 5-June 23, 1985): Printed Ephemera Thursdays Music(May 9-June 20, 1985): Printed Ephemera (Box 40, Folder I.A.873)
    - "Proposal for 42nd Venice Biennale/Artschwager/Chamberlain/Samaras", circa 1984; Large photo transparencies and checklists. (Box 40, Folder I.A.874)
    - "Norwegian Exhibition", 1984; Correspondence regarding a proposed show. (Box 40, Folder I.A.875)
    - "S.F.S.F. Robert Atkins", 1984; Includes curator statement, correspondence, checklist of insurance valuations, loan forms and condition reports, and background material on various artists. San Francisco/Science Fiction(September 27-October 28, 1984): Checklist; Art and Event Photographs; Loan Forms and Condition Reports; General Exhibition Documentation; Restricted material removed: Loan forms and condition reports. (Box 40, Folder I.A.876)
    - Special Projects 1984: "Suruchi Chan", 1983-1984; Includes numerous letters from the artist and handwritten checklist. Special Projects (Fall 1984) (October 14-December 9, 1984): Printed Ephemera; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 41, Folder I.A.877)
    - Special Projects (Fall 1984): Vincent Tangredi, Contract only. Special Projects (Fall 1984) (October 14-December 9, 1984): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 41, Folder I.A.878)
    - Special Projects (Fall 1984): Stacey Spiegel, Includes handbill and contract. Special Projects (Fall 1984) (October 14-December 9, 1984): Printed Ephemera (Box 41, Folder I.A.879)
    - Fashion (Fall 1984): Valborg Fletre Linn, Brochure, contract, press release and one piece of correspondence. Fashion (Fall 1984):Valborg Fletre Linn(October 14-December 9, 1984): Press Release; Printed Ephemera (Box 41, Folder I.A.880)
    - Special Projects (Fall 1984): Victoria Weill, Contract only. Special Projects (Fall 1984) (October 14-December 9, 1984): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 41, Folder I.A.881)
    - Special Projects (Fall 1984): Jon Kessler, Special Projects (Fall 1984) (October 14-December 9, 1984): Art and Event Photographs; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 41, Folder I.A.882)
    - Special Projects (Fall 1984): Andrew Moszynski, Special Projects (Fall 1984) (October 14-December 9, 1984): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 41, Folder I.A.883)
    - Special Projects (Fall 1984): Maryanne Breen, Contract only. Special Projects (Fall 1984) (October 14-December 9, 1984): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 41, Folder I.A.884)
    - Special Projects (Fall 1984): Rolando A. Briseno, Special Projects (Fall 1984) (October 14-December 9, 1984): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 41, Folder I.A.885)
    - Special Projects (Fall 1984): Art Spellings, Special Projects (Fall 1984) (October 14-December 9, 1984): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 41, Folder I.A.886)
    - Joyce Kozloff, 1984; Catalogue and materials regarding the unrealized exhibition of Kozloff's installation created for the Harvard Square T station, Cambridge, Massachusetts. (Box 41, Folder I.A.887)
    - New York City Artist Housing Program Material, 1984; Materials on program started by the city. (Box 41, Folder I.A.888)
    - "Mechanisms Travel Proposal", 1984; Information on the exhibition in its travelling version. New Art Machines(October 14-December 9, 1984): Checklist; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 41, Folder I.A.889)
    - ID: Third World Women Photographers… And Other Exhibition Materials, 1984; Includes checklists and original proposal and other correspondence from curator Lucy Lippard. Also includes small quantity of materials for Telex: Iran. Gilles Peress: "Telex Iran"(October 14-December 9, 1984): General Exhibition Documentation ID: An Exhibition of Third World Woman Photographers(October 14-December 9, 1984): Checklist; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 41, Folder I.A.890)
    - Miscellaneous Film Materials, 1984; Stray notes and documents concerning the 1984 film program. (Box 41, Folder I.A.891)
    - Henry Geldzahler, 1984; Material relating to Geldzahler's assumption of the post of guest curator, including correspondence from Geldzahler, his typescript proposal for the exhibition Underknown and other items. Also includes small amount of material on the Michael Hurson exhibition at the Clocktower. Michael Hurson: Drawings 1969-1983(February 26-March 25, 1984): General Exhibition Documentation Underknown(October 14-December 9, 1984): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 41, Folder I.A.892)
    - Underknown, 1984; Correspondence, essay text by curator Henry Geldzahler, introduction text by Alanna Heiss, notes and budget. Underknown(October 14-December 9, 1984): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 41, Folder I.A.893)
    - "Underknown: Loan Forms", 1984; Loan forms with correspondence and insurance documents. Underknown(October 14-December 9, 1984): Loan Forms and Condition Reports; Restricted material removed: Loan forms. (Box 41, Folder I.A.894)
    - "Underknown: Values", 1984; Checklists of insurance valuations. Underknown(October 14-December 9, 1984): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 41, Folder I.A.895)
    - Underknown, 1984; Mainly correspondence. Underknown(October 14-December 9, 1984): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 41, Folder I.A.896)
    - "Underknown Returns", 1984; Numerous artwork return materials; with the exhibition catalogue. Underknown(October 14-December 9, 1984): Printed Ephemera; General Exhibition Documentation; Restricted material removed: Shipping documents. (Box 41, Folder I.A.897)
    - "Underknown Show File", 1984; Includes return sheets, loan forms, some correspondence, and checklists. Underknown(October 14-December 9, 1984): Checklist; Loan Forms and Condition Reports; General Exhibition Documentation; Restricted material removed: Loan forms and shipping documents. (Box 42, Folder I.A.898)
    - "Underknown Show File", 1984; Return forms and loan sheets only. Underknown(October 14-December 9, 1984): Loan Forms and Condition Reports; Entire folder restricted. (Box 42, Folder I.A.899)
    - Underknown Artwork Photographs, 1984; Numerous photographs of paintings and artworks from the exhibition. Underknown(October 14-December 9, 1984): Art and Event Photographs (Box 42, Folder I.A.900)
    - Photographs of India and Paintings by Suruchi Chand, undated; Possibly related to Chand's special project. Special Projects (Fall 1984) (October 14-December 9, 1984): Art and Event Photographs (Box 42, Folder I.A.901)
    - Underknown, 1984-1986; Underknown loan documents with invoices from the later exhibition. Underknown(October 14-December 9, 1984): Loan Forms and Condition Reports; General Exhibition Documentation Images of the Unknown(April 13-June 15, 1986): General Exhibition Documentation; Entire folder restricted. (Box 42, Folder I.A.902)
    - Labor Intensive Abstraction, 1984; Small amount of correspondence and artist information. Labor Intensive Abstraction: An Exhibition of Highly Detailed Abstract Paintings and Drawings(November 8-December 8, 1984): General Exhibition Documentation; The documents in this folder have been severely damaged by water; patrons must use gloves when handling these materials. (Box 42, Folder I.A.903)
    - Dorit Cypis Press Packet, 1984; The documents in this folder have been severely damaged by water; patrons must use gloves when handling these materials. (Box 42, Folder I.A.904)
    - Exhibition Proposals, 1984; Miscellaneous correspondence regarding proposals for exhibitions, with some ephemera. (Box 42, Folder I.A.905)
    - Artwork and Installation Slides and Transparencies, 1984-2003; Most labeled. Robert Grosvenor(January 22-March 18, 1984): Installation Photographs Fresh Paint: The Houston School(May 5-June 23, 1985): Installation Photographs National and International Studio Program Exhibition 1988-89(April 23-June 12, 1989): Art and Event Photographs Arnold Mesches: FBI Files(September 23, 2002-February 2, 2003): Art and Event Photographs (Box 42, Folder I.A.906)
    - Merle Temkin Clocktower Proposal, circa 1984-1986; Installation proposal with CV and other materials on the artist. (Box 42, Folder I.A.907)
    - Fred Tommaselli, circa 1985; News clippings, CV, artwork photographs and slides, and other materials on the artist; likely related to the exhibition Out of the Studio. Out of the Studio: Art with Community(January 25-March 22, 1987): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 42, Folder I.A.908)
    - Special Projects (Winter 1985): Emily Jennings, 1984-1985; Special Projects (Winter 1985) (January 13-March 10, 1985): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 42, Folder I.A.909)
    - Special Projects (Winter 1985): Joanne Brockley, Contract only. Special Projects (Winter 1985) (January 13-March 10, 1985): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 42, Folder I.A.910)
    - "Special Projects Winter 1985", Unlabelled, likely installation photographs of various works, with separate list of captions for images of special projects that season. Special Projects (Winter 1985) (January 13-March 10, 1985): Installation Photographs; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 42, Folder I.A.911)
    - "Winter 1985 Miscellaneous Information", Lists of special project artists and room assignments, and studio program artists and their studio locations. (Box 43, Folder I.A.912)
    - Special Projects (Winter 1985): Paul H-O, Contract and background information; the artist was apparently closely related to the "SF/SF" organization or exhibition. San Francisco/Science Fiction(September 27-October 28, 1984): General Exhibition Documentation Special Projects (Winter 1985) (January 13-March 10, 1985): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 43, Folder I.A.913)
    - "Special Projects (Winter 1985): Checklist", Checklist of works in the special projects rooms and other exhibition spaces. Synesthetics: Writers and Artists(January 13-March 10, 1985): Checklist Special Projects (Winter 1985) (January 13-March 10, 1985): Checklist (Box 43, Folder I.A.914)
    - Special Projects (Winter 1985): Jean Luc Poivoir, Special Projects (Winter 1985) (January 13-March 10, 1985): Art and Event Photographs; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 43, Folder I.A.915)
    - Special Projects (Winter 1985): William Mutter, Contract only Special Projects (Winter 1985) (January 13-March 10, 1985): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 43, Folder I.A.916)
    - Special Projects (Winter 1985): Rhonda Zwilliger, One slide of artwork and note only. Special Projects (Winter 1985) (January 13-March 10, 1985): Art and Event Photographs; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 43, Folder I.A.917)
    - Special Projects (Winter 1985): David Winter, Contact information only. Special Projects (Winter 1985) (January 13-March 10, 1985): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 43, Folder I.A.918)
    - Special Projects (Winter 1985): Alan Kirili, On sheet of caption information ("Hawkeye 8, 9, + 10 1984") for an outdoor project (as indicated on original folder label); not known if realized. (Box 43, Folder I.A.919)
    - Special Projects (Winter 1985): Francisco Munoz, Special Projects (Winter 1985) (January 13-March 10, 1985): Art and Event Photographs; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 43, Folder I.A.920)
    - Special Projects (Winter 1985): Tina Girouard, Contract only. Special Projects (Winter 1985) (January 13-March 10, 1985): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 43, Folder I.A.921)
    - Fashion (Winter 1985): Richard Flood/Cara Perlman, Artwork photographs, project description, and notes. Fashion (Winter 1985):Cara Pearlman: Dressing Down(January 13-March 10, 1985): Art and Event Photographs; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 43, Folder I.A.922)
    - Video (Winter 1985), Still images of videos, background information, and notes. Video (Winter 1985):Expropriated TV Images(January 13-March 10, 1985): Art and Event Photographs; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 43, Folder I.A.923)
    - "Nothing Lasts Forever Movie", 1984-1985; Notes and correspondence regarding the screening of a film. Film (Winter 1985) (January 19-March 3, 1985): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 43, Folder I.A.924)
    - "Sculpture Winter", 1985; Curatorial statements for the two exhibitions below, with press materials and notes. Figures: Sculpture in the Auditorium(January 13-March 10, 1985): General Exhibition Documentation Synesthetics: Writers and Artists(January 13-March 10, 1985): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 43, Folder I.A.925)
    - Figures, 1985; Installation and artwork photographs, loan forms, insurance valuation checklist, background material on artists, with some correspondence. Figures: Sculpture in the Auditorium(January 13-March 10, 1985): Installation Photographs; Art and Event Photographs; Loan Forms and Condition Reports; Restricted material removed: loan forms. (Box 43, Folder I.A.926)
    - "3 AM Jonathan Weinberg", 1985; Background information on the artists, artwork slides, and curatorial statement. 3 A.M.(January 13-March 10, 1985): Art and Event Photographs; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 43, Folder I.A.927)
    - Synaesthetics, 1984; Includes texts by and about the participants, artwork photographs, lists of the artistic pairings of artists and writers. Synesthetics: Writers and Artists(January 13-March 10, 1985): Art and Event Photographs; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 43, Folder I.A.928)
    - Synaesthetics Loan Forms, 1984; Synesthetics: Writers and Artists(January 13-March 10, 1985): Loan Forms and Condition Reports; Entire folder restricted. (Box 43, Folder I.A.929)